<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Open Plant Pathology</title>
    <link>https://openplantpathology.org/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Open Plant Pathology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://openplantpathology.org/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plant Pathologist&#39;s Guide to Writing Your First R Package</title>
      <link>https://openplantpathology.org/post/a-plant-pathologist-s-guide-to-writing-your-first-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openplantpathology.org/post/a-plant-pathologist-s-guide-to-writing-your-first-r-package/</guid>
      <description>So You Want to Write an R Package? So you want to write your first R package, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start? We can help with that! Writing an R package is not difficult per se, but it can be intimidating for a first timer. Why would you want to write an R package? Well, as @PhytophthoraLab says, if you have more than two functions, you have a package, plus it means you can get citations!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPP Interviews: Sophien Kamoun</title>
      <link>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-11-13-interview-kamoun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-11-13-interview-kamoun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src = &#34;/img/members/kamoun.jpg&#34; style = &#34;border-radius: 50%; border-color: white 1px; margin: 30px; float: right&#34;&gt;
We talked with Prof. Sophien Kamoun, a biology scientist with the Sainsbury Laboratory, Norwich, UK. Dr. Kamoun is known for his prolific Tweeting and advocacy for Open Science but, also importantly, for his work with oomycetes (#notafungus), effectors and evolution and, more recently, wheat blast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPP Interviews: Niklaus J. Grünwald</title>
      <link>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-08-26-interview-grunwald/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-08-26-interview-grunwald/</guid>
      <description>&lt;img src = &#34;/img/members/grunwald.jpg&#34; style = &#34;border-radius: 50%; border-color: white 1px; margin: 30px; float: right&#34;&gt; Get to know one of our leaders, Dr. Niklaus J. Grünwald, a plant pathologist with USDA ARS, Corvallis, OR, USA. Nik has made significant scientific contributions to the understanding of the population biology and evolution of &lt;em&gt;Phytophthora infestans&lt;/em&gt; worldwide and developed R packages to advance and facilitate the analysis of genetic and genome sequence data with applications in taxonomy and evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is going on in OPP? a quick summary of the first five months</title>
      <link>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-05-20-second-post-five-month-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-05-20-second-post-five-month-summary/</guid>
      <description>OPP was created in early January and we had no idea how OPP would be received and whether it would catch interest and be sustainable. In this post, we provide a brief summary of major achievements during the first five months of OPP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you a scientist dealing with computational plant pathology? Then let&#39;s connect and code together!</title>
      <link>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-01-08-first-post-community-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://openplantpathology.org/post/2018-01-08-first-post-community-call/</guid>
      <description>A community call for plant epidemiologists, pathogen population biologists, molecular ecologists and mathematical modelers to join a network for promoting data sharing and open tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>