<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Open Plant Pathology</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Open Plant Pathology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2020</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What are Brazilian plant pathologists doing? a text-analysis of scientific poster titles</title>
      <link>/post/2019-08-25-text-analysis-brazil-abstracts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-08-25-text-analysis-brazil-abstracts/</guid>
      <description>A text analysis of the titles of more than 700 scientific posters to be presented at the 51 CBFito in Brazil using web scraping, text mining and wordcloud for visulization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you getting ready for ensuring reproducibility in Plant Pathology? We want to hear!</title>
      <link>/post/2019-08-21-survey-reproducible-practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-08-21-survey-reproducible-practices/</guid>
      <description>We are calling for participation in a survey to gain understanding of the status of reproducible research practices among plant pathologists. Please donate only five minutes of your time to answer a survey questionnaire with 16 multiple choice questions about your current practices related to organisational procedures, data management, analytical workflows and sharing of scientific information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breaking down barriers between remote sensing and plant pathology</title>
      <link>/post/2019-07-20-letter-rene-heim-tpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-07-20-letter-rene-heim-tpp/</guid>
      <description>This is a preprint of a Letter to Editor of Tropical Plant Pathology by Heim &lt;em&gt;et al.&lt;/em&gt; on the challenges and potential solutions in the context of application of remote sensing in plant pathology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPP Interviews: Jade d’Alpoim Guedes and Ben Marwick</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-25-interview-jade-ben/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-25-interview-jade-ben/</guid>
      <description>In our third OPP Interview we have the privilege to chat with two prestigious computational scientists, representatives of the field of archaeology, about their experiences on the use, tool development and promotion of reproducible research practices in science.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fall of an Empire</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-25-the-fall-of-an-empire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2019 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-25-the-fall-of-an-empire/</guid>
      <description>Emerson describes how he made use of the &lt;em&gt;gganimate&lt;/em&gt; package to help visualize the yearly variation in the efficacy of a fungicide used to control soybean rust in Brazil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Plant Pathologist&#39;s Guide to Writing Your First R Package</title>
      <link>/post/a-plant-pathologist-s-guide-to-writing-your-first-r-package/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-plant-pathologist-s-guide-to-writing-your-first-r-package/</guid>
      <description>So you want to write your first R package, but you don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start? We can help with that! Writing an R package is not difficult, but it can be intimidating for a first timer. Why would you want to write an R package? Read more to find out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPP Interviews: Sophien Kamoun</title>
      <link>/post/2018-11-13-interview-kamoun/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-11-13-interview-kamoun/</guid>
      <description>We talked with Prof. Sophien Kamoun, a biology scientist with the Sainsbury Laboratory, Norwich, UK. Dr. Kamoun is known for his prolific Tweeting and advocacy for Open Science but, also importantly, for his work with oomycetes (#notafungus), effectors and evolution and, more recently, wheat blast.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OPP Interviews: Niklaus J. Grünwald</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-26-interview-grunwald/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-26-interview-grunwald/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; Get to know one of our leaders, Dr. Niklaus J. Grünwald, a plant pathologist with USDA ARS, Corvallis, OR, USA. Nik has made significant scientific contributions to the understanding of the population biology and evolution of &lt;em&gt;Phytophthora infestans&lt;/em&gt; worldwide and developed R packages to advance and facilitate the analysis of genetic and genome sequence data with applications in taxonomy and evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is going on in OPP? a quick summary of the first five months</title>
      <link>/post/2018-05-20-second-post-five-month-summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 May 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-05-20-second-post-five-month-summary/</guid>
      <description>OPP was created in early January and we had no idea how OPP would be received and whether it would catch interest and be sustainable. In this post, we provide a brief summary of major achievements during the first five months of OPP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are you a scientist dealing with computational plant pathology? Then let&#39;s connect and code together!</title>
      <link>/post/2018-01-08-first-post-community-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-01-08-first-post-community-call/</guid>
      <description>A community call for plant epidemiologists, pathogen population biologists, molecular ecologists and mathematical modelers to join a network for promoting data sharing and open tools.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>